<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>EAGER: Evolutionary History and Paleoecology of the Last Old World Hipparion Superlineage</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>02/01/2012</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>01/31/2014</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>30009</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Standard Grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>06030207</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Geosciences</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Earth Sciences</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>H. Richard Lane</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>This project will stimulate a new international research initiative between Howard University, the Los Angeles Counnty Museum of Natural History, and the Institute of Vertebrate Paleontology and Paleoanthropology (CAS), Beijing. It leverages expertise and specialized skills, facilities, and/or other resources of the foreign collaborator(s) and access to the collections at the Natural History Museum of Ethiopia. Chinese colleagues are seeking funding from the Chinese Natural National Science Foundation to facilitate their research on this project and for the training of a Chinese national student at Howard University. PIs will develop web content and e-exhibits on hipparion evolution, biogeography and paleodiet for all involved institutions at Howard University. The innovative high risk-high return nature of this proposal makes it a suitable fit for an EAGER. Letters of collaboration and permission for access to relevant Ethiopian museum collections are provided.</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>01/23/2012</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>06/18/2013</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1113175</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Raymond</FirstName>
      <LastName>Bernor</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>rbernor@howard.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>01/23/2012</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>Howard University</Name>
      <CityName>Washington</CityName>
      <ZipCode>200599000</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>2028064759</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>2400 Sixth Street N W</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>District of Columbia</StateName>
      <StateCode>DC</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>7570</Code>
      <Text>SURFACE EARTH PROCESS SECTION</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>7298</Code>
      <Text>COLLABORATIVE RESEARCH</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
