<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>Investigating and Supporting the Development of Ambitious and Equitable Mathematics Instruction at Scale</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>08/15/2011</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>07/31/2016</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>3075340</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Continuing grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>11090000</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Education &amp; Human Resources</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Research on Learning in Formal and Informal Settings (DRL)</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>James E. Hamos</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>The Development of Ambitious and Equitable Mathematics Instruction project is supporting and investigating the implementation of reformed mathematics instruction at the middle school level in two large school districts. Project researchers are asking: What does it take to support mathematics teachers' development of ambitious and equitable instructional practices on a large scale? The project has built on what was learned in a previous, successful project studying the implementation of a middle school mathematics curriculum. The primary goal of the new project is to develop an empirically grounded theory of action for implementing reform at school and district levels. The researchers are investigating reform within a coherent system that focuses on leadership and school-based professional development. In addition, they are facilitating a longitudinal study of the curriculum implementation by continuing the data collection from the original study. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; In order to build a theory of action, the project team is synthesizing data from a variety of domains including instructional systems (e.g., curriculum, materials, professional development, support for struggling students, and learning communities), mathematics coaching, networks of teachers, school leadership, and district leadership. Investigators are using a variety of analytic techniques to successfully integrate both quantitative and qualitative data as they seek to understand how school district strategies are playing out in schools and classrooms and how those strategies can be revised in order to improve student learning of mathematics.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; An empirically grounded theory of action for implementing reform will help the mathematics education community to implement and to understand the process of reforming mathematics instruction at the middle school level. Many advances in mathematics instruction have been documented within a limited context, but researchers and practitioners need to understand the full range of action necessary to achieve similar successes at a district-wide level. The model developed from this project, in conjunction with longitudinal data, has the potential to guide future reform efforts that seek to provide ambitious and equitable mathematics instruction.</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>07/21/2011</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>08/06/2012</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1119122</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Kara</FirstName>
      <LastName>Jackson</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>kara.jackson@mcgill.ca</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>07/21/2011</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Paul</FirstName>
      <LastName>Cobb</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>paul.cobb@vanderbilt.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>07/21/2011</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Ken</FirstName>
      <LastName>Frank</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>kenfrank@msu.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>07/21/2011</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Thomas</FirstName>
      <LastName>Smith</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>thomas.smith@vanderbilt.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>07/21/2011</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Ilana</FirstName>
      <LastName>Horn</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>ilana.horn@vanderbilt.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>07/21/2011</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>Vanderbilt University</Name>
      <CityName>NASHVILLE</CityName>
      <ZipCode>372407830</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>6158756070</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>Office of Sponsored Programs</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Tennessee</StateName>
      <StateCode>TN</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>7645</Code>
      <Text>DISCOVERY RESEARCH K-12</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
