<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>NSF I/UCRC 5-Year Renewal, Phase III</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>09/01/2011</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>08/31/2016</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>141505</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Continuing grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>07070003</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Engineering</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Industrial Innovation and Partnerships</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Rathindra DasGupta</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>IIP 1134684 &lt;br/&gt;University of Cincinnati; Lee &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;IIP 1134676 &lt;br/&gt;University of Michigan; Ni &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;IIP 1134721 &lt;br/&gt;Missouri University of Science and Technology; Sarangapani &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The NSF Industry/University Cooperative Research Center (I/UCRC) on Intelligent &lt;br/&gt;Maintenance Systems (IMS) was established in 2001. This proposal builds upon the accomplishments of the previous ten years and seeks funding to continue supporting a three campus operation among the University of Cincinnati (leading institution), the University of Michigan, and Missouri Univ. of S&amp;T. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Center addresses the underlying issues in machine degradation modeling and prediction as well as develops the transformational technology in advanced prognostics. Over the past 10 years, the Center has developed systematic methodology and tools that made evident impacts to a number of member companies including Toyota, G.M., Boeing, P&amp;G, and National Instruments, amongst others. Over the next five years, the Center intends to advance the scientific base as well as to validate the developed tools to further accelerate the deployment and commercialization of the developed technologies. The center also plans to have international sites in Singapore, Brazil and Spain. In addition, the Center plans to develop spin-off companies with a compelling Marketing Plan in order to commercialize its tools through its member company, National Instruments, in 2011. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The IMS IUCRC fills an important niche to maintain industry global competiveness by continuous improvement of manufacturing effectiveness and efficiency. The center educates students and its membership through an extensive system of internship and scholar exchanges as well as international workshops and courses. IMS has developed and continues to execute an effective system for innovation and IP generation. The Center plans to develop spin-off companies with a compelling Marketing Plan in order to commercialize its tools through its member company, National Instruments, in 2011.</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>08/23/2011</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>02/28/2013</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1134684</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Yan</FirstName>
      <LastName>Chen</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>chen2yn@mail.uc.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>02/28/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Jay</FirstName>
      <LastName>Lee</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>jay.lee@uc.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>08/23/2011</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Edzel</FirstName>
      <LastName>Lapira</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>lapiraer@mail.uc.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>02/28/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>University of Cincinnati Main Campus</Name>
      <CityName>Cincinnati</CityName>
      <ZipCode>452210222</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>5135564358</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>University Hall, Suite 530</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Ohio</StateName>
      <StateCode>OH</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>1714</Code>
      <Text>SPECIAL PROJECTS - CISE</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>5761</Code>
      <Text>INDUSTRY/UNIV COOP RES CENTERS</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
