<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>RUI: ARTS. Revision of the poorly known frog genus Chiasmocleis (Anura, Microhylidae)</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>02/01/2012</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>01/31/2015</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>314165</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Standard Grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>08010206</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Biological Sciences</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Environmental Biology</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Elizabeth Friar</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>The study proposes a revision of a poorly known group of semifossorial frogs that occurs throughout the Neotropical lowlands east of the Andes from Panama to southern Brazil. This group has never been thoroughly studied to determine its species composition, species boundaries, and cryptic speciation in the group. The revision will be an important addition to understanding diversity and speciation of the Neotropical biota. Currently, most of the Neotropical biota is poorly understood with regard to species diversity and individual species distributions. Preliminary data suggest that morphological variation is a poor estimate of genetic diversity among Amazonian frogs. The researchers intend to study the composition of this group of frogs using a combined approach of molecular and morphological characters.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The proposal will result in publications in scientific journals and a monographic revision of the group. The project involved collaborations with scientists throughout Latin America. It will also directly support the training of two undergraduates per year at the University of Richmond. Furthermore, the project will strengthen international scientific collaboration by training of two Brazilian researchers. A specific aim of the project is to train research collaborators and interested undergraduates on synthetic and revisionary monographic work</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>01/24/2012</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>04/23/2013</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1144692</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Rafael</FirstName>
      <LastName>De Sa</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>rdesa@richmond.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>01/24/2012</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>University of Richmond</Name>
      <CityName>RICHMOND</CityName>
      <ZipCode>231730001</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>8042898100</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>202 MARYLAND HALL</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Virginia</StateName>
      <StateCode>VA</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>7375</Code>
      <Text>Advanc Revisionary Taxon &amp; Sys</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
