<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>RUI: Climate change and birds: links among earlier nesting, migratory strategies, and warmer winters</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>04/01/2012</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>03/31/2015</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>156250</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Standard Grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>08010208</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Biological Sciences</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Environmental Biology</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Douglas Levey</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>Climate change effects on the timing of breeding seasons have been well documented for many bird species. Birds may breed earlier because warmer spring temperatures cause earlier plant growing seasons and, consequently, insect prey becomes more abundant earlier in the year. In southwest Idaho, American kestrels are breeding almost a month earlier than they did 20 years ago; however, spring temperatures and plant growing seasons have not changed significantly during that time period. One explanation is that more individuals are spending the winter on or near their breeding ground. If so, it is important to understand the fitness consequences of this shift in behavior. This project will examine whether kestrels that remain on the breeding area year-round 1) nest earlier in the year, 2) obtain better territories or 3) produce more offspring, compared to kestrels that leave the breeding area for the winter. While many studies have suggested how climate change may negatively affect bird populations, in this system, milder winters may be resulting in more year-round residency, earlier breeding, and potentially, population stability or growth. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This project will promote partnerships among community members, including private landowners, universities, and local non-profits. It will also provide education and training opportunities for undergraduate and graduate students while supporting an early-career female researcher. Results from this project will be relevant for nationwide bird monitoring programs and management plans.</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>03/26/2012</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>04/22/2013</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1145552</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Julie</FirstName>
      <LastName>Heath</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>julieheath@boisestate.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>03/26/2012</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>Boise State University</Name>
      <CityName>boise</CityName>
      <ZipCode>837251135</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>2084261574</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>1910 University Drive</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Idaho</StateName>
      <StateCode>ID</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>1182</Code>
      <Text>POP &amp; COMMUNITY ECOL PROG</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>9150</Code>
      <Text>EXP PROG TO STIM COMP RES</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
