<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>NeTS: EAGER: C2RN: Towards Cognitive Cognitive Radio Networks</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>09/01/2011</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>08/31/2014</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>145000</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Standard Grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>05050000</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Computer &amp; Information Science &amp; Engineering</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Computer and Network Systems</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Min Song</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>This project develops unified cognitive network management architecture for end-to-end application-oriented quality of service (QoS) provisioning in heterogeneous cognitive radio networks. The core of the architecture is a unified cross-layer controller, which has two control plans: vertical nodal control plan and horizontal network control plan. The nodal cross-layer optimized resource allocation is guided by the control policy dynamically generated by horizontal network control based on a cognitive agent network, and thus leads to a multi-scale cross-layer architecture for distributive and autonomous application-oriented QoS provisioning for future cognitive radio networks. The transformative significance is two-fold. First, characterizing and understanding the end-to-end network behaviors of cognitive radio networks is of major fundamental research interest. Second, cognitive network management is a technique to implement end-to-end application-oriented QoS provisioning under various randomness and uncertainty in cognitive radio networks. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This project provides solutions for a variety of domain-specific applications while addressing future societal needs. By using cognitive network management to implement end-to-end application-oriented QoS provisioning under various randomness and uncertainty in cognitive radio networks, this project benefits other kinds of networks such as the 3G/4G mobile networks, and WLAN/WMAN/WWAN. The research findings will be integrated into networking courses. Research results will be disseminated in journals and conferences.</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>08/06/2011</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>08/06/2011</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1145596</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Song</FirstName>
      <LastName>Ci</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>sci@engr.unl.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>08/06/2011</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</Name>
      <CityName>LINCOLN</CityName>
      <ZipCode>685880430</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>4024723171</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>312 N 14TH STREET</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Nebraska</StateName>
      <StateCode>NE</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>7363</Code>
      <Text>RES IN NETWORKING TECH &amp; SYS</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
