<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag> 
  <Award> 
    <AwardTitle>CAREER: Analysis of microRNA function in maize inflorescence development</AwardTitle>  
    <AwardEffectiveDate>06/01/2012</AwardEffectiveDate>  
    <AwardExpirationDate>05/31/2017</AwardExpirationDate>  
    <AwardAmount>566518</AwardAmount>  
    <AwardInstrument> 
      <Value>Continuing grant</Value> 
    </AwardInstrument>  
    <Organization> 
      <Code>08090100</Code>  
      <Directorate> 
        <LongName>Directorate for Biological Sciences</LongName> 
      </Directorate>  
      <Division> 
        <LongName>Division of Integrative Organismal Systems</LongName> 
      </Division> 
    </Organization>  
    <ProgramOfficer> 
      <SignBlockName>Amy Litt</SignBlockName> 
    </ProgramOfficer>  
    <AbstractNarration>This project will elucidate the role of small RNAs in determining inflorescence architecture. Plant architechture is largely determined by the genetic mechanisms regulating patterns of cell division, specification and early differentiation that occur in special structures called meristems. The architecture elaborated by the inflorescence meristem is especially important because it controls reproductive patterning. For example, the tassel and ear of maize are inflorescences and, thus, the processes that regulate their architecture control such things as the number and position of seeds that will form. This project aims to understand how a key class of gene regulatory molecules called microRNAs regulate maize inflorescence architecture. The project centers on a mutant, fuzzy tassel (fzt), that affects a key enzyme required for producing microRNAs and plants with the fzt mutation display severe defects in inflorescence development affecting both the tassel and the ear. The project will employ genetic, molecular, and genomic approaches to identify microRNAs with key roles in inflorescence developement and link specific microRNAs and microRNA target genes to discrete stages of inflorescence development. Modulating expression of microRNAs or microRNA target genes could be used manipulate inflorescence architecture and ultimately increase yield. This project will also enhance science education by providing authentic research experiences for high school, community college, and early college students. The project will have a major impact because these groups often do not have access to independent research experiences. For example, community college students will participate in a summer internship program and this is expected to ease their transition to a four year curriculum including science. A research based genetics lab course will also be implemented, allowing undergraduate students to participate in authentic research as part of the normal biology curriculum.</AbstractNarration>  
    <MinAmdLetterDate>02/09/2012</MinAmdLetterDate>  
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>02/09/2012</MaxAmdLetterDate>  
    <ARRAAmount/>  
    <AwardID>1148971</AwardID>  
    <Investigator> 
      <FirstName>Beth</FirstName>  
      <LastName>Thompson</LastName>  
      <EmailAddress>thompsonb@ecu.edu</EmailAddress>  
      <StartDate>02/09/2012</StartDate>  
      <EndDate/>  
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode> 
    </Investigator>  
    <Institution> 
      <Name>East Carolina University</Name>  
      <CityName>Greenville</CityName>  
      <ZipCode>278584353</ZipCode>  
      <PhoneNumber>2523289540</PhoneNumber>  
      <StreetAddress>Office of Sponsored Programs</StreetAddress>  
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>  
      <StateName>North Carolina</StateName>  
      <StateCode>NC</StateCode> 
    </Institution>  
    <ProgramElement> 
      <Code>1118</Code>  
      <Text>PLANT FUNGAL &amp; MICROB DEV MECH</Text> 
    </ProgramElement>  
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>1329</Code>
      <Text>PLANT GENOME RESEARCH PROJECT</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award> 
</rootTag>
