<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>Growth and Enhancement of the Scholarship for Service Program at Mississippi State University</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>08/15/2012</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>07/31/2017</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>1608091</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Continuing grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>11040000</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Education &amp; Human Resources</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Undergraduate Education</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Victor P. Piotrowski</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>Mississippi State University (MSU), a 2001/2004/2007/2012 Center of Academic Excellence in Information Assurance Education (CAE) recipient and a CyberCorps(R): Scholarship for Service (SFS) participating university since 2002 continues to produce SFS students for the government at a rate of approximately 10 new SFS students a year. This project supports approximately 39 students in one of six technical disciplines over a five year period (17 undergraduates, 20 M.S. students, and 2 PhD students). This program continues to be professionally organized and administered by those most closely associated with the Information Assurance program at MSU. The program continues to benefit from over $19M research funding from DOJ, DOD and NSF as each student funded under this initiative is required to participate in a research experience. MSU continues a strong working relationship with other CAEs, other universities, community colleges, and the law enforcement community. MSU graduates are successful in government service and new scholarship recipients are sought after by additional government employers.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;MSU has a strong track record of building strong relationships with schools aspiring to be capable of running a scholarship program. They have partnered with several HBCUs including Jackson State University, Mississippi Valley State University, and Tuskegee University, as well as other schools, such as the University of South Alabama, the University of Texas at Tyler, and Saint Cloud State University. This project continues that work to ensure that more schools build IA programs that can provide graduates to help fill the cybersecurity workforce.</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>08/18/2012</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>08/18/2012</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1241722</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Rayford</FirstName>
      <LastName>Vaughn</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>ray.vaughn@uah.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>08/18/2012</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>David</FirstName>
      <LastName>Dampier</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>dampier@cse.msstate.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>08/18/2012</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Yoginder</FirstName>
      <LastName>Dandass</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>yogi@cse.msstate.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>08/18/2012</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>Mississippi State University</Name>
      <CityName>MISSISSIPPI STATE</CityName>
      <ZipCode>397629662</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>6623257404</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>PO Box 6156</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Mississippi</StateName>
      <StateCode>MS</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>1668</Code>
      <Text>FED CYBER SERV: SCHLAR FOR SER</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
