<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>Integrating Concept Mapping with Laboratory Experimentation and the 5E Learning Cycle to Improve Student Conceptual Understanding in a Foundational Engineering Course</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>04/01/2013</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>03/31/2016</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>199998</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Standard Grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>11040200</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Education &amp; Human Resources</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Undergraduate Education</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Louis J. Everett</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>This project is integrating concept mapping, laboratory instrumentation, and the 5E learning cycle to improve student conceptual understanding in a foundational course on engineering dynamics. Engineering dynamics is typically a high enrollment course nationally and is required of students in Mechanical, Aerospace, Civil, and Bio Engineering programs. One study indicated that national success rates in dynamics is approximately 53%. Because the course is taken early in the undergraduate program, poor performance can often be the cause of low graduation rates. This project is meeting three goals: (1) improve student conceptual understanding of dynamics, (2) cultivate student interest in learning dynamics, and (3) to understand if and to what extent the use of the proposed pedagogical model impacts student learning outcomes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This project is the first of its kind to integrate these three proven instructional approaches to improve student conceptual understanding in dynamics. Building on previous work this study will have a national impact on STEM education.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Assessment instruments contain both quantitative and qualitative components and the study includes control and quasi-experimental groups utilizing pre and post testing.</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>06/21/2013</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>06/21/2013</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1244700</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Ning</FirstName>
      <LastName>Fang</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>ning.fang@usu.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>06/21/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>Utah State University</Name>
      <CityName>Logan</CityName>
      <ZipCode>843221415</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>4357971226</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>Sponsored Programs Office</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Utah</StateName>
      <StateCode>UT</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>7513</Code>
      <Text>TUES-Type 1 Project</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
