<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>SNM: A Versatile Microplasma-based Patterning Technology for Large-Scale, High Throughput Nanomanufacturing</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>09/15/2012</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>08/31/2016</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>1208381</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Standard Grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>07030000</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Engineering</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Civil, Mechanical, and Manufacturing Innovation</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Bruce M. Kramer</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>This grant provides funding for the development of a microplasma-based, direct-write fabrication tool to produce sub-100 nm metallic and metal oxide device structures on rigid and flexible substrates. The patterned structures will be formed by selective electrochemical reduction of metal ions dispersed in polymeric films by plasma electrons. Different metals will be explored including Ag, Au, Pt, Cu, and Ti. To control the pattern dimension, a durable nanostencil masking technology will be incorporated into the process. Simulations and experiments will be performed to explore and elucidate the relationship between the stencil geometry and charged fluid transport that ultimately determines the pattern transfer and scaling. Concurrently, nanolayered polymer substrates with moisture barrier properties suitable for durable flexible electronics will be developed. The two process technologies will be integrated on a roll-to-roll line to demonstrate process compatibility and scalability. The resulting metallic nanostructures will be evaluated for such properties as electrical conductivity, adhesion, density, surface roughness, pattern fidelity, and responses to applied strains. Accelerated lifetime testing will be performed to assess the viability of the structures in commercial applications.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;If successful, this research will result in a highly versatile, low-cost, high-throughput method for the fabrication of nanoscale structures and functional devices on flexible substrates. The microplasma-based patterning process is operated near room temperature, making it compatible with a wide variety of substrates ranging from silicon to polymers, and at atmospheric pressure, making it readily scalable to continuous production systems. The technology has the potential to complement state-of-the-art, direct-write nanofabrication systems currently used in silicon CMOS electronics, as well as creating new opportunities to fabricate nanoscale devices for flexible electronics and sensors. Additionally, integration of the microplasma tool with nanolayered polymer substrates could enable the development of flexible electronic systems for moisture latent environments including implantable medical microsystems.</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>09/14/2012</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>06/25/2013</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1246715</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Christian</FirstName>
      <LastName>Zorman</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>caz@case.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>09/14/2012</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>R. Mohan</FirstName>
      <LastName>Sankaran</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>mohan@case.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>09/14/2012</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Joao</FirstName>
      <LastName>Maia</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>joao.maia@case.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>09/14/2012</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Philip</FirstName>
      <LastName>Feng</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>philip.feng@case.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>09/14/2012</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>Case Western Reserve University</Name>
      <CityName>CLEVELAND</CityName>
      <ZipCode>441064901</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>2163684510</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>Nord Hall, Suite 615</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Ohio</StateName>
      <StateCode>OH</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>1674</Code>
      <Text>NANOSCALE: INTRDISCPL RESRCH T</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>1788</Code>
      <Text>NANOMANUFACTURING</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
