<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>CAREER: Understanding Robustness of Cellular Organization in Escherichia Coli through Nanofabricated Environments</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>03/01/2013</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>02/28/2018</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>82461</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Continuing grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>08070600</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Biological Sciences</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Molecular and Cellular Biosciences</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Gregory W. Warr</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>This project explores the robustness of cellular organization, specifically the chromosome and the cell division apparatus of the bacterium E. coli. Engineered micro-fabricated and nano-fabricated environments will be used to physically constrain cells and control their chemical environment. Techniques of fluorescence and super-resolution microscopy, combined with quantitative image analysis, will be used to study local and macro-domain level organization of chromosomes, and the assembly of cell division proteins in a variety of constrained cell shapes and chemical environments. These studies will advance our understanding of the mechanisms that maintain cellular organization and their underlying robustness.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Broader Impacts. In addition to advancing design principles for nanofabrication, this project will provide training opportunities for graduate, undergraduate and high school students. This project will also engage undergraduate students who aim to become teachers of STEM disciplines in scientific research, and it will provide research experiences for students from under-represented groups through the Tennessee Louis Stokes Alliance for Minority Participation program.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award is co-funded by the Programs in Cellular Dynamics and Function and the Physics of Living Systems</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>02/28/2013</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>02/28/2013</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1252890</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Jaan</FirstName>
      <LastName>Mannik</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>jmannik@utk.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>02/28/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>University of Tennessee Knoxville</Name>
      <CityName>KNOXVILLE</CityName>
      <ZipCode>379960003</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>8659743466</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>1 CIRCLE PARK</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Tennessee</StateName>
      <StateCode>TN</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>1114</Code>
      <Text>Cellular Dynamics and Function</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>7246</Code>
      <Text>PHYSICS OF LIVING SYSTEMS</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
