<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>LTREB: Social dynamics and fitness in a complex primate society</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>06/15/2013</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>05/31/2018</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>89970</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Continuing grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>08090500</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Biological Sciences</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Integrative Organismal Systems</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Bruce Cushing</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>Very little is known about how complex mammalian societies develop from the interaction of individual social behaviors. In dynamic/fluid social groups, two critically important questions are: what brings smaller core groups together, and the flip side of what splits them apart? The research in this study will study the highly social Old World Monkey geladas (Theropithecus gelada). Geladas are an excellent model system to address this question as they have complex social groups and are easy-to-observe terrestrial animals that live at high densities. This research uses a combination of demographic and behavioral data, social network analyses, and population genetic data to pinpoint the individual gelada behaviors that contribute directly to their social complexity. Additionally, using behavioral, life-history, physiological, and reproductive measures, this research will measure the costs and benefits of different social interactions. The results of this research will establish not just how complex societies emerge from individual behaviors but also why the individuals exhibit those particular behaviors, representing a critical step in understanding how some animals, like humans, moved from simple to complex societies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The long-term project has and will continue to: (1) strengthen collaborative relationships both within the U.S. and between the U.S. and Africa; (2) provide training to American and Ethiopian undergraduate, masters, and Ph. D. students; (3) assist conservation efforts in Ethiopia through the preservation of national parks, (4) provide outreach both within Ethiopia (offering regular seminars on gelada behavioral ecology to both Ethiopian nationals and international tourists), and within the U.S. (through interactive lectures for K-12 students). Specifically, the members of this project have spear-headed Michigan Primate Outreach, which involves a series of age-appropriate lectures on primates and conservation for students of all ages (see project website for all outreach activities: http://www.umich.edu/~gelada/UMGRP/Home.html).</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>06/03/2013</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>06/03/2013</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1255974</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Thore</FirstName>
      <LastName>Bergman</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>thore@umich.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>06/03/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Jacinta</FirstName>
      <LastName>Beehner</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>jbeehner@umich.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>06/03/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>University of Michigan Ann Arbor</Name>
      <CityName>Ann Arbor</CityName>
      <ZipCode>481091271</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>7347647247</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>3003 South State St.</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Michigan</StateName>
      <StateCode>MI</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>7659</Code>
      <Text>ANIMAL BEHAVIOR</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
