<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>Explosive Radiation, Extreme Phenotypic Diversity and the Evolution of Morphotypes within Ant Nest Beetles</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>02/15/2013</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>01/31/2016</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>178407</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Continuing grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>08010206</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Biological Sciences</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Environmental Biology</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Simon Malcomber</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>Researchers from the University of Arizona will use molecular phylogenetic, morphological and ecological data within Ant Nest Beetles (genus Paussus) to explore the evolution of bizarre phenotypic traits and host ant shifts across geographic landscapes at two taxonomic scales. This project investigates putative "replicated adaptive radiations" within this group, a rare phenomenon in which geographically separated lineages are composed of species exhibiting the same sets of convergently evolved phenotypes and ecological niches. It also will provide a framework to investigate the drivers, stages, and relative rates of phyletic and phenotypic change within an adaptive radiation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This project includes formal and informal education and training components, including postdoctoral, graduate and undergraduate training in the areas of evolutionary biology, insect systematics, taxonomy and identification, and biogeography. It will help to formalize collaborations between young scientists and students from the United States, Italy, Sri Lanka and India. Beetle identification workshops, involving up-and-coming students and faculty, will be offered in these countries covering modern beetle classification, morphology, collection, and identification resources. Researchers will generate online tutorials that clearly demonstrate examples of species radiation and convergent evolution that will be immediately understandable by the public.</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>02/05/2013</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>02/05/2013</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1256976</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>James</FirstName>
      <LastName>Robertson</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>erotylid@gmail.com</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>02/05/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Wendy</FirstName>
      <LastName>Moore Brusca</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>wmoore@email.arizona.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>02/05/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>University of Arizona</Name>
      <CityName>TUCSON</CityName>
      <ZipCode>857210001</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>5206266000</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>888 N Euclid Ave</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Arizona</StateName>
      <StateCode>AZ</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>1171</Code>
      <Text>PHYLOGENETIC SYSTEMATICS</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
