<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>Collaborative Research: Coupling Mantle Volatiles, Eruption Dynamics, and Tectonics on the Mid-Atlantic Ridge</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>07/01/2013</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>06/30/2015</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>282844</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Continuing grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>06040200</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Geosciences</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Ocean Sciences</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Donna Blackman</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>Mapping and sampling of a portion of the mid-Atlantic spreading center, where a unique geochemical signature was determined for a 1980's 'popping rock' sample, will take advantage of recent recognition that tectonic deformation may play a role in focusing volatile fluxing from the mantle. Geophysical mapping, targeted sampling by ROV, and a complete suite of post-cruise geochemical analyses aim to determine whether the early quantification of mantle volatiles was representative for the region and/or whether such signatures cluster only near faults, thus implying localized fluxing. Such finding could uproot long-standing inferences about background mantle volatile contents. Students will be introduced to marine research and a postdoc will delve into a new aspect of spreading center processes. Collaboration with IPGP France will train these young scientists in integrated, international, interdisciplinary geoscience.</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>06/12/2013</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>06/12/2013</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1259218</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Josh</FirstName>
      <LastName>Curtice</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>jcurtice@whoi.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>06/12/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution</Name>
      <CityName>WOODS HOLE</CityName>
      <ZipCode>025431041</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>5082892462</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>183 OYSTER POND ROAD</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Massachusetts</StateName>
      <StateCode>MA</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>1620</Code>
      <Text>MARINE GEOLOGY AND GEOPHYSICS</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
