<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rootTag>
  <Award>
    <AwardTitle>I/UCRC: in Energy-Smart Electronic Systems (ES2) - Site</AwardTitle>
    <AwardEffectiveDate>06/01/2013</AwardEffectiveDate>
    <AwardExpirationDate>05/31/2018</AwardExpirationDate>
    <AwardAmount>60000</AwardAmount>
    <AwardInstrument>
      <Value>Continuing grant</Value>
    </AwardInstrument>
    <Organization>
      <Code>07070003</Code>
      <Directorate>
        <LongName>Directorate for Engineering</LongName>
      </Directorate>
      <Division>
        <LongName>Division of Industrial Innovation and Partnerships</LongName>
      </Division>
    </Organization>
    <ProgramOfficer>
      <SignBlockName>Rathindra DasGupta</SignBlockName>
    </ProgramOfficer>
    <AbstractNarration>Center for Energy Smart Electronic Systems (ES2) &lt;br/&gt;IIP-1265675; Georgia Tech (GT); Yogendra Joshi &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This proposal FROM Georgia Tech seeks to join the Center for Energy Smart Electronic Systems (ES2) comprised of the State University of New York (SUNY, lead institution), the University of Texas at Arlington, and Villanova University. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In collaboration with other ES2 partners, GT will focus on the development of systematic methodologies for operating electronic systems, including data centers, as dynamic self-sensing and regulating systems that are predictive and verified in real time. Algorithms will be developed to control cooling resources and to assist expert system schedulers to schedule and/or migrate workload to achieve optimal energy consumption. Thermal management resources will also be allocated dynamically in response to system needs. This is by nature an intrinsically multi-disciplinary research area integrating software algorithms, control systems, thermal management and hardware. New models will have direct application to a variety of electronic/computing systems ranging all the way from the chip or device level to the system or data center level. Problem-oriented research related to Software Systems, Control Systems, Thermal Management Protocols, and Implementation and Assessment, will be addressed during the Centers first five year program. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;GT, along with other ES2 partners, will participate in promoting significant reductions in energy consumption in electronic systems, and will contribute to the national agenda of pursing transformative technology breakthroughs that will help us meet our energy challenges. In partnership with other ES2 sites, GT will implement an effective data management plan that promotes the sharing of data, models, and practices generated by the Center with academia and industry. These disseminated resources will strength the competitiveness of our nations industries in this sector. As part of ES2, the GT Site is committed to attracting talented and motivated students from all groups, and will integrate a variety of mechanisms across the partners, including enhancement of existing minority pipeline programs to exceed participation by women (35%) and underrepresented students (20%). Students will have access to research data center facilities to conduct experiments.</AbstractNarration>
    <MinAmdLetterDate>05/22/2013</MinAmdLetterDate>
    <MaxAmdLetterDate>05/22/2013</MaxAmdLetterDate>
    <ARRAAmount/>
    <AwardID>1265675</AwardID>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Yogendra</FirstName>
      <LastName>Joshi</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>yogendra.joshi@me.gatech.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>05/22/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>1</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Minami</FirstName>
      <LastName>Yoda</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>minami@gatech.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>05/22/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Investigator>
      <FirstName>Satish</FirstName>
      <LastName>Kumar</LastName>
      <EmailAddress>satish.kumar@me.gatech.edu</EmailAddress>
      <StartDate>05/22/2013</StartDate>
      <EndDate/>
      <RoleCode>2</RoleCode>
    </Investigator>
    <Institution>
      <Name>Georgia Tech Research Corporation</Name>
      <CityName>Atlanta</CityName>
      <ZipCode>303320420</ZipCode>
      <PhoneNumber>4048944819</PhoneNumber>
      <StreetAddress>Office of Sponsored Programs</StreetAddress>
      <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
      <StateName>Georgia</StateName>
      <StateCode>GA</StateCode>
    </Institution>
    <ProgramElement>
      <Code>5761</Code>
      <Text>INDUSTRY/UNIV COOP RES CENTERS</Text>
    </ProgramElement>
  </Award>
</rootTag>
